Guide to the Amos Burg Photographs 1889-1986
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Amos Burg, His Family, and His Adventures, 1889-1950; Subgroup 1
  - Adventurer/Lecturer/Writer, 1920-1950; Series C
    - Canoe trip--Columbia River from source to mouth, 1924-1925; Subseries 5; 56 photographs.
      - Reaching the mouth of the Columbia, 1925 January (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Canoe trip--Snake River headwaters to Columbia River mouth, 1925; Subseries 6; 115 photographs,
      The prints documenting this daring trip include a group glued to loose album pages and another group of loose prints. Burg started the trip in his beloved canoe, Song O' the Winds, but he had to replace it with another after it was smashed up in the Grand Canyon of the Snake. Most of the photographs document the Snake River leg of the journey, especially Hells Canyon. Of special note is a group of images of Bill Hissom, homesteader on the Snake River Plains who was of African-American and Mohawk Indian heritage. Burg became good friends with him and visited Hissom's homestead during the canoe voyage. Also included is a small group of images made by newsreel cameramen documenting Burg's descent of the Cascades of the Columbia. Among them are reproductions of the newsreel headlines.
      - Album 450-3--selected pages, 1925 (Box-folder 2/6)
        Jackson Lake and Dam (p. 39), Hells Canyon (p. 89), Burg at Idaho Falls, canoe at Lake Walcott, and Si Bullock (p. 98)
      - Album pages, 1925 (Box-folder 5/1)
        In addition to the Snake River/Columbia trip, Burg has intermingled a small number of prints of friends and one of a ship's officer from his seaman service. Nearly all of the prints are identified by location.
      - Loose prints, 1925 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Bill Hissom and his homestead, Snake River Plains, 1925 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Shooting the Cascades of the Columbia, 1925 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Canoe trip--Alaska Inside Passage to Seattle, 1926; Subseries 7; 19 photographs.
      Documents canoe trip by Amos Burg and Fred Hill (Spoke) from Skagway to Ketchikan. Includes portrait of the two men on Standard Service oil tanker, on which they worked their way from Ketchikan back to Seattle.
      - Inside Passage to Seattle--loose prints, 1926 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Inside Passage to Seattle--prints in Album 450-3 (pp. 4-5, 82-83, 90-91, 93-95), 1926 (Box-folder 2/5, 2/7)
    - Canoe trip--Columbia River, headwaters to mouth, 1926; Subseries 8; 47 photographs.
      Documents trip by Amos Burg and Fred Hill (Spoke) after they and the canoe, Song O' the Winds, rode the rails from Seattle to Columbia Lake, B.C. A notable group of prints (5/9) shows them portaging the canoe around Celilo Falls and running the rapids below the falls.
      - River scenes--British Columbia, 1926 (Box-folder 5/6, Box-folder 2/5-7)
        Documents location of David Thompson's 1814 campsite, the Big Bend region, Canoe River, Downie Creek, Double Eddy Creek, Kinnabasket Lake, and Windermere. Includes farewell to Bob Blackmore, who was locally famous for his voyage around the Big Bend and images of Sluice Box Pete, a miner in the area. Album 450-3 (2/5) includes Columbia Lake, a sawmill at Golden (where Burg and Hill worked for a time), a fire in the Big Bend country, and Windermere (pp. 6-7), mouth of Canoe River and a miner (p. 44), Canal Flats and "Indian Jim" on horseback (pp. 54-55), Big Bend and Downie Creek (p.74), Surprise Rapids (p. 84, 87), Patch Island Camp, Ed Robinson and Sid Webber (trappers, Big Bend country), and repairing canoe (p. 85), Beavermouth (p. 86), and various images (p. 93).
      - River scenes--Washington state, 1926 (Box-folder 5/7, Box-folder 2/5)
        Documents Kettle Falls area, including Indian fishery and the Old Mission, as well as the steamboat, Bridgeport at Pateros. Album 450-3 (2/5, 2/7) includes: canoeists at Priest Rapids (pp. 1, 92),
      - River scenes--unidentified locations, 1926 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - River scenes--Celilo Falls, St. Helens, 1926 (Box-folder 5/9, Box-folder 2/7)
        Portaging Celilo Falls and running rapids below also in Album 450-3 (2/7), pp. 72, 75
    - Alaska-Yukon Expedition, 1928; Subseries 9; 66 photographs.
      - Burg--in kayak and with dogs, 1928 (Box-folder 5/10)
      - Juneau to Lake Bennett, 1928 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - Yukon River, 1928 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - Yukon River--reindeer herd crossing, 1928 (Box-folder 5/13)
      - Nome to King Island, 1928 (Box-folder 5/14)
      - Locations, unidentified, 1928 (Box-folder 5/15)
      - Images that appeared in National Geographic [and similar views], 1928 (Box-folder 5/16)
        Article, "To-day on 'The Yukon Trail of 1898'," July 1930.
    - Mackenzie River Expedition, 1929; Subseries 10; 49 photographs.
      - Amos Burg, Dr. George Rebec, and their canoe, 1929 (Box-folder 5/17)
      - Athabaska River, 1929 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Mackenzie River, 1929 (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Peel Portage, Fort McPherson to LaPierre House, 1929 (Box-folder 5/20)
        Burg used one image from this portage for Christmas cards. See 5/24.
      - Fort Yukon, 1929 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Fort Yukon--Dr. Grafton Burke and Hospital, 1929 (Box-folder 5/22)
      - People--unidentified locations, 1929 (Box-folder 5/23)
      - Amos Burg's Christmas card image--Peel Portage, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 5/24)
      - Images that appeared in National Geographic [and similar views], 1929 (Box-folder 5/25)
        "On Mackenzie's Trail to the Polar Sea," August 1931
    - Canoe trip--Canoe River to Columbia and downriver to Portland, 1930 June-July; Subseries 11; 89 photographs.
      - Map [photographic reproductions on post card stock], 1930 June-July (Box-folder 6/1)
      - British Columbia--Canoe River, 1930 June (Box-folder 6/2)
      - British Columbia--Columbia River, 1930 June-July (Box-folder 6/3)
      - British Columbia--Brilliant [including Dukabor settlement], 1930 June-July (Box-folder 6/4)
      - Washington (state)--Columbia River, 1930 July (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Washington (state)--Indian people at Kettle Falls and Colville, 1930 July (Box-folder 6/6)
      - Oregon and Washington (state)--Columbia River, 1930 July (Box-folder 6/7)
      - Unidentified locations and people, 1930 June-July (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Canoe trip--Snake River and Columbia River to Portland, 1930 August; Subseries 12; 90 photographs.
      - Amos Burg and canoe, 1930 August (Box-folder 6/9)
      - Prints on album pages, 1930 August (Box-folder 6/10)
      - Locations--identified, 1930 August (Box-folder 6/11)
      - Locations--unidentified, 1930 August (Box-folder 6/12)
      - People--unidentified, 1930 August (Box-folder 6/13)
      - Possibly Snake, Columbia or Canoe Rivers--Amos Burg and canoe, 1930 June-August (Box-folder 6/14)
      - Possibly Snake, Columbia or Canoe Rivers--locations and people, unidentified, 1930 June-August (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Nonesuch Island (Bermuda) Expedition, New York Zoological Society, 1931 June; Subseries 13; 5 photographs (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Around the World on Yacht Camargo, 1931-1932; Subseries 14; 757 photographs
      - Amos Burg, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Views of Camargo, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Camargo crew, 1931 (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Julius and Dorette Fleischmann, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Charles Fleischmann III (Skipper), 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Dorette Louise Fleischman [baby], 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/6)
      - Fleischmann children and nannies, Mademoiselle and Miss Jean, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Fleischmann party, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Album pages [photographic copies], 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Bermuda, 1931 October (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Jamaica, 1931 October (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Barbados, 1931 October (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Cocos Island (Pacific off Costa Rica)--rescue of castaways, 1931 October (Box-folder 7/13)
      - Marquesas, 1931 November (Box-folder 7/14)
      - New Britain, 1931 November (Box-folder 7/15)
      - New Hebrides, 1931 December (Box-folder 7/16)
      - Tahiti, 1931 December (Box-folder 7/17)
      - Fiji, 1931 December (Box-folder 7/18)
      - Tonga, 1931 December (Box-folder 7/19)
      - Solomon Island, 1931 December (Box-folder 7/20)
      - New Guinea and Dutch East Indies, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 7/21)
      - Bali, 1932 (Box-folder 7/22-23)
      - Java, 1932 (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Borneo--Labuan and Sarawak, 1932 (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Philippineso--Manila, 1932 (Box-folder 8/3)
      - Indo-China--Annam, 1932 (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Indo-China--Cochin China, 1932 (Box-folder 8/5)
      - Indo-China--Chami ruins, 1932 (Box-folder 8/6)
      - Cambodia, 1932 (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Thailand--Bangkok, 1932 (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Singapore, 1932 (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Sumatra, 1932 (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Nias, 1932 (Box-folder 8/11)
      - Ceylon, 1932 (Box-folder 8/12)
      - Aden, 1932 (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Arabian Desert--Bedouins, 1932 (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Egypt, 1932 (Box-folder 8/15)
      - Eastern Mediterranean, 1932 (Box-folder 8/16)
      - Unidentified--boats and ships, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/17)
      - Unidentified--cities and towns, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/18)
      - Unidentified--crafts and markets, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/19)
      - Unidentified--monuments and landmarks, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/20)
      - Unidentified--people, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/21)
      - Unidentified--scenic views, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - A Native Son's Rambles in Oregon--article for National Geographic [February 1934, pp. 173-234], 1932; Subseries 15; 57 photographs
      - Agriculture, 1932 (Box-folder 9/1)
      - Celilo Falls, 1932 (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Columbia River Highway--bridges, 1932 (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Crater Lake, 1932 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - John Day River valley, 1932 (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Klamath Lake--black crowned night heron, 1932 (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Lumber industry, 1932 (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Oregon State Game Farm--pheasants, 1932 (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Mill--unidentified, 1932 (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Oregon Caves, 1932 (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Pendleton Roundup, 1932 (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Portland, 1932 (Box-folder 9/12)
      - Rogue River--Hell's Canyon Bridge construction [?], 1932 (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Captions Burg wrote for submitted photos, 1932 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Admiralty Island, Alaska--trip to film Giants of the North, 1932; Subseries 16; 57 photographs (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Cape Horn Expedition, 1933-1934; Subseries 17; 458 photographs; 28 lantern slides hand colored
      Burg refitted a former U.S. Coast Guard surf boat, which was christened Dorjun by one of his sponsors, the Julius and Dorette Fleischmann family. The McCormick Steamship Co. of San Francisco, for which Burg had done freelance work, shipped the Dorjun to Buenes Aires aboard the West Mahwah, and Burg shipped as supercargo to save funds for the expedtion. One of his fellow seamen, Roy Pepper, volunteered to make the expedition with him. They and the Dorjun reshipped aboard the steamship Jose Menendez to Punta Arenas (Magellanes) on the Strait of Magellan, from where they started the expedition in the Dorjun, towing a dory, the Cabo de Hornos, whi National Geographic ch Burg obtained from a miner for $16. Burg's assignment for on the trip was to photograph and write about the native people of the sourthern end of the hemisphere, including the Yahgan, Alacaluf, Ona, and Haush. The trip resulted in a National Geographic article, "Inside Cape Horn," published with Burg's photographs in December 1937.
      - Trip on West Mahwah, 1933 (Box-folder 9/16)
      - Map [photographic reproduction], 1933 (Box-folder 9/17)
      - Markers and monuments, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Images published in National Geographic [December 1937], 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/19)
      - Burg and crew, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/20)
      - Dorjun and Cabo de Hornos--at sea, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Dorjun and Cabo de Hornos--inshore, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Dorjun --inshore for repairs, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Magellanes/Punta Arenas, Chile, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Magellanes to Santa Ana Point (Port Famine/Fort Bulnés), 1933 (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Dawson Island, 1933 (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Offing Island, 1933 (Box-folder 10/4)
        Includes views of "jackass" penguins, named after their braying vocal effects.
      - Gabriel Channel, 1933 (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Brecknock Pass, 1934 (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Yendegaia Bay (and Beagle Channel), 1934 (Box-folder 10/7)
        Includes resupply by Chilean naval transport, Micalvi.
      - Ushuaia, Argentina, 1934 (Box-folder 10/8)
        Includes views of penitentiary.
      - Navarino Island and vicinity, 1934 (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Hoste Island, Chile, 1934 (Box-folder 10/10)
      - Yahgan people [Tierra del Fuego], 1934 (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Yahgan people--Domingo and family, 1934 (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Punta Arenas to Puerta Montt aboard Chilean naval sailing vessel, Baquedano, 1934 (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Birds, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/14)
      - People, their activities and settlements, unidentified, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/15)
      - Ships and boats, unidentified, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Views--mountains and glaciers, unidentified, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Views--sea and islands, unidentified, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/18)
      - Hand colored glass lantern slides, 1933-1934 (Box 19)
        Amos Burg used these 28 images from the Cape Horn Expedition to illustrate his lectures.
      - Visit with friends in Santiago, Chile, and vicinity after Cape Horn Expedition, 1934
        - Arica, 1934 (Box-folder 10/19)
        - LaSerena, 1934 (Box-folder 10/20)
        - Santiago, 1934 (Box-folder 10/21)
        - Santiago--Carlos and Olga [?] and family, 1934 (Box-folder 10/22)
        - Santiago--Edwards home, 1934 (Box-folder 10/23)
        - Valparaiso, 1934 (Box-folder 10/24)
        - On yacht, Aconcagua, 1934 (Box-folder 10/25)
        - Locations, unidentified, 1934 (Box-folder 10/26)
        - People, unidentified, 1934 (Box-folder 10/27)
      - Flag presentation to Argentine officials, 1934 (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Buenos Aires, Argentina--on shipboard, 1934 (Box-folder 10/29)
      - Barbados, 1934 (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Pope and Talbot Lumber Co. film job, 1935; Subseries 18; 13 photographs (Box-folder 11/1)
      Amos Burg made his first commercial film for Pope and Talbot, filming the company's trestles, culverts, docks, and bridges from Vancouver, B.C., to San Diego, Calif.
    - Dorjun trip through Inside Passage, Seattle, Wash., to Skagway, Alaska, 1936; Subseries 19; 29 photographs
      - British Columbia, 1936 (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Alaska, 1936 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Trip to England, 1937; Subseries 20; 36 photographs
      Amos Burg sailed to England aboard the liner, America, to cover the coronation of King George VI for National Geographic. Then, in an American canoe shipped to England, he paddled canals from London to Liverpool. Burg produced an article for National Geographic, "Britain Just Before the Storm" (August 1940, pp. 185-212), and he filmed Canal Children of England for ERPI Classroom Films.
      - London, 1937 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Canals and boats, 1937 (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Locations, unidentified, 1937 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - People, unidentified, 1937 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Green River and Colorado River run, 1938; Subseries 21; 215 photographs
      Amos Burg took the first inflatable rubber raft to film Haldane Holmstrom (Buzz) recreating his 1937 one-man voyage in a wooden boat he constructed himself. Holmstrom made the 1937 trip from Green River Lakes in Wyoming to Hoover (then called Boulder) Dam in 52 days. The re-creation took 70 days. Willis D. Johnson joined the crew at Green River, Utah. Paul Douglas narrated the resulting film, Conquering the Colorado, which was distributed by 20th Century Fox and won an Academy Award nomination for short subjects. Both men also used the film on lecture tours.
      - Trip from Aug. 26 through Sept. 2, with Holmstrom and Burg, 1938 (Box-folder 11/9)
      - Trip from Sept. 2-circa Sept. 20, with Holmstrom and Burg, 1938 (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Trip from circa Sept. 20-Nov. 8, with Holmstrom, Burg, and Johnson, 1938 (Box-folder 11/11-12)
      - Trip with Holmstrom and Burg, undated, 1938 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Middle Fork Salmon River (Idaho), 1939 June; Subseries 22; 40 photographs (Box-folder 12/1)
      Amos Burg ran the Middle Fork Salmon River with Dr. Russell G. Fracier, physician for Admiral Byrd's Antarctic Expedition, and six Utah boatmen. Paramount Pictures bought the resulting film, Seeing Is Believing.
    - The Cattlemen film project--Modoc County, Calif., 1939 August; Subseries 23; 62 photographs (Box-folder 12/2-3)
      Amos Burg inspected several ranches in California before selecting the Christensen Ranch in Modoc County for the ERPI film. He took his rubber raft along on the trip and packed it on his back between streams.
    - International House, New York City, N.Y., circa 1940; Subseries 24; 215 photographs (Box-folder 12/4)
      Portraits of Chinese actresses at International House.
    - Asian trip for ERPI Classroom Films, 1940; Subseries 25; 70 photographs
      Amos Burg was assigned to make three films, Children of Japan, Children of China, and People of Western China, working under wartime conditions. He spent four months filming in Japan under close supervision of officials and produced a film that pleased the Japanese Department of Tourism. To make the China films, Burg flew China National Airways into wartorn Chungking, then by truck to Chengtu, where he lived with missionary teachers and filmed Children of China. With Chengut as a hub, he ranged into the foothills of the Himalayas to film People of Western China. In Kobe, Japan, on the return trip to San Francisco aboard the SS President Pierce, Burg was detained briefly on suspicion of being a spy.
      - Voyage to Japan on Tatuta Maru, 1940 March (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Children of Japan project, 1940 (Box-folder 12/6-7)
      - Children of China project, Chungking, 1940 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Alaska trip for ERPI Classroom Films and National Geographic, 1941; Subseries 26; 84 photographs
      Burg sailed out of the Columbia River on his sloop, Endeavor, for Alaska. He filmed Alaska: Reservoir of Resources and Eskimo Children.
      - Alaska: Reservoir of Resources, 1941 (Box-folder 12/9)
      - Alaska: Reservoir of Resources--Bristol Bay, dog and sleds, 1941 (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Alaska: Reservoir of Resources--Bristol Bay fisheries, 1941 (Box-folder 12/11)
      - Alaska: Reservoir of Resources--Nakneck River fisheries, 1941 (Box-folder 12/12)
      - Eskimo Children--air travel to Nunivak Island, 1941 (Box-folder 12/13)
      - Eskimo Children--Mekoryuk village, Nunivak Island, 1941 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - West Indies to Central America trip for ERPI, 1943; Subseries 27; 5 photographs (Box-folder 12/15)
      Burg made two films on the two regions. The prints in this subseries are from Guatemala and Cuba.
    - Colombia and Venezuela trip for ERPI, 1944; Subseries 28; 85 photographs
      From Bogota, Amos Burg traveled Colombia mostly by railway and river steamer on the Magdalena. The subseries includes one image from Venezuela; the remainder are from Colombia. Burg filmed Colombia and Venezuela and produced a National Geographic article, "Cruising Colombia's Ol' Man River" (May 1947, pp. 615-660)
      - Agriculture and farms, 1944 (Box-folder 12/16)
      - Agriculture--banana groves, 1944 (Box-folder 12/17)
      - Airplanes, 1944 (Box-folder 12/18)
      - Art, 1944 (Box-folder 12/19)
      - Burros, 1944 (Box-folder 12/20)
      - Churches, 1944 (Box-folder 12/21)
      - Flowers, 1944 (Box-folder 12/22)
      - Guahiba Indians, 1944 (Box-folder 12/23)
      - Landscape views, 1944 (Box-folder 12/24)
      - Magdalena River--riverboats, 1944 (Box-folder 12/25)
      - Magdalena River--shore scenes, moving cargo, 1944 (Box-folder 12/26)
      - Magdalena River--views, 1944 (Box-folder 12/27)
      - Netmaking, 1944 (Box-folder 12/28)
      - Railroads, 1944 (Box-folder 12/29)
      - Road building, 1944 (Box-folder 12/30)
      - Ruins--Indian, 1944 (Box-folder 12/31)
      - Ruins--Spanish, 1944 (Box-folder 12/32)
      - Tree felling, 1944 (Box-folder 12/33)
      - Unidentified people, 1944 (Box-folder 12/34)
      - Unidentified towns, 1944 (Box-folder 12/35)
      - Venezuela--Rio Orinoco, 1944 (Box-folder 12/36)
    - New York City for Encyclopedia Britannica Films, 1944; Subseries 29; 38 photographs (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Alaska trip on Endeavor, 1946; Subseries 30; 157 photographs
      After refurbishing the Endeavor at Astoria, Amos Burg sailed tieh Inside Passage, joined at Prince Rupert, B.C., by Dick and Maeline Taylor and their son, Dickey, who made the trip on their cabin cruiser, Como Reto. Burg wrote an article for National Geographic, "Endeavor Sails the Inside Passage" (June 1947, pp. 801-828).
      - Refitting Endeavor at Astoria, 1946 (Box-folder 13/2)
      - Seattle to Prince Rupert, B.C., 1946 (Box-folder 13/3)
      - Prince Rupert, B.C., 1946 (Box-folder 13/4)
      - Prince Rupert, B.C., to Ketchikan, Alaska, 1946 (Box-folder 13/5)
      - Ketchikan, Alaska, 1946 (Box-folder 13/6)
      - Sitka, Alaska, 1946 (Box-folder 13/7)
      - Shipwreck remains, 1946 (Box-folder 13/8)
      - Juneau, Alaska, 1946 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Ketchikan, 1947; Subseries 31; 2 photographs (Box-folder 13/10)
      Amos Burg lived aboard Endeavor and worked for the Alaska Sportsman magazine. Prints in this subseries are of Burg's dog, King, performing on a stage.
    - British Isles for Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1947; Subseries 32; 11 photographs (Box-folder 13/11)
      Amos Burg filmed British Isles. Prints in this subseries are of coal mining in Scotland.
    - Spain for Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1947-1948; Subseries 33; 153 photographs
      Amos Burg filmed Spanish Children in the village of Torremolinos. He also filmed Iberian Peninsula throughout Spain and Portugal. The storyboards for Spanish Children, included in this subseries, show how Burg used his still photographs to set up scenes for filming.
      - Bicycle tour, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 13/12)
      - La Roca, Malaga, 1948 (Box-folder 13/13)
      - Mediterranean coast, 1948 (Box-folder 13/14)
      - Ronda, Marbella, and El Chorro, 1948 (Box-folder 13/15)
      - Unidentified locations, 1948 (Box-folder 13/16)
      - Unidentified people, 1948 (Box-folder 13/17-18)
      - Spanish Children storyboards, 1948 (Box-folder 14/1-10)
      - Spanish Children prints not used on storyboards, 1948 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - British Children for Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1948; Subseries 34; 6 photographs (Box-folder 14/12)
      Amos Burg filmed British Children in walled city of York.
    - Scandinavian trip for Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1949; Subseries 35; 267 photographs
      Amos Burg filmed Norwegian Children on Hardanger Fjord and Scandinavia, covering a Norwegian sailor, a Danish farmer, and a Swedish steelworker. Nearly all of the images in this subseries are of Norway.
      - Cruise on DS Nordstjernen, 1949 (Box-folder 14/13)
      - Cruise on DS Nordstjernen--unidentified port, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/14)
      - Cruise on DS Nordstjernen--crew members, 1949 (Box-folder 14/15)
      - Cruise on DS Nordstjernen--passengers, 1949 (Box-folder 14/16)
      - Cruise on DS Nordstjernen--passengers, Indrelid family [?], 1949 (Box-folder 14/17)